Thanh-Danh NGUYEN

M.Sc., Computer Science Researcher

Email: danhnt.it (at) gmail.com Phone number: (+84) 33 220 5141 Portfolio: danhntd.github.io

BIOLOGY

Danh Nguven obtained his M.Sc and B.Sc. (Honors) Degrees in Computer Science from University of Information Technology (UIT), Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City (VNUHCM) in 2024 and 2021, respectively. He currently works as a researcher at the Laboratory of Multimedia Communications, UIT, VNUHCM. Prior to that, he contributed to Sugimoto Lab., City Science Lab., and VietAI Organization as a research intern, data science engineer, and teaching assistant, respectively. His research interests include Computer Vision and Applications, Deep Learning, and Data Science. His research projects are under the supervision of Dr. Tiep Nguyen and Prof. Tam V. Nguyen.

Research Interests. Computer Vision and Applications, Deep Learning and Data Science.

EDUCATION

University of Information Technology, VNUHCM

HCMC, Vietnam

M.Sc. in Computer Science

Dec 2021-Dec 2023

B.Sc. in Computer Science (Honors)

Aug 2017-Apr 2021

Thesis: Semantic Image Segmentation in the Dark with Domain Adaptation Method

Thesis: Camouflage Instance Segmentation via Highly-Distinguished Features

EXPERIENCE

Official Researcher

MMLab., University of Information Technology, VNUHCM - mmlab.uit.edu.vn

HCMC, Vietnam Jun 2021-present

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Aug 2019-Jun 2021

- Research Computer Vision and its applications::
 - * Semantic scene understanding, instance segmentation
 - * Low-shot learning for object detection and instance segmentation
 - * Conditional image generation and reconstruction
- Host and join academic research projects
- Give lectures on Computer Vision, Deep Learning and Applications

VietAI Organization - vietai.org

Vietnam

Teaching Assistant

Oct 2021-present

- Operate AI courses: A-Star Bootcamp for Startups, Machine Learning, Train-the-Trainer, Advanced Computer Vision, etc.

Sugimoto Lab., National Institute of Informatics, Japan - dgcv.nii.ac.jp

Tokyo, Japan

Research Intern

Mar 2023-Sep 2023

- Medical Image Instance Segmentation with Contrastive Learning (Advisors: Prof. Akihiro Sugimoto and Dr. Nghia Le)

City Science Lab. @Ho Chi Minh City - CSL@HCMC

HCMC, Vietnam

Data Science Engineer

Apr 2021-Oct 2022

- Collaborate with MIT Media Lab., L3-Cities Team to apply Cityscope Urban Analytics Technology to HCMC
- In charge of backend process for Urban Indicators Analytics

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- 1. **Thanh-Danh Nguyen**, Bich-Nga Pham, Trong-Tai Dam Vu, Vinh-Tiep Nguyen, Thanh Duc Ngo, and Tam V. Nguyen. "InstSynth: Instance-wise Prompt-guided Style Masked Conditional Data Synthesis for Scene Understanding." 2024 International Conference on Multimedia Analysis and Pattern Recognition (MAPR). IEEE, 2024. (Scopus)
- 2. **Thanh-Danh Nguyen***, Anh-Khoa Nguyen Vu*, Nhat-Duy Nguyen*, Vinh-Tiep Nguyen, Thanh Duc Ngo, Thanh-Toan Do, Minh-Triet Tran, and Tam V. Nguyen, "Few-shot Camouflaged Animal Detection and Segmentation", *CV4Animals Workshop*, *CVPR 2022*. (invited poster)
- 3. **Thanh-Danh Nguyen**, Nguyen Phan, Tam V. Nguyen, Vinh-Tiep Nguyen, and Minh-Triet Tran, "Nighttime Scene Understanding with Label Transfer Scene Parser". (under review)
- 4. Sy-Tuyen Ho, Manh-Khanh Ngo Huu, **Thanh-Danh Nguyen**, Nguyen Phan, Vinh-Tiep Nguyen, Tam V. Nguyen, Thanh Duc Ngo, and Duy-Dinh Le, "APGAN: Abstraction-Perception Preserving Cartoon Face Synthesis", *Multimedia Tools and Applications*, May 2022. IF = 2.577 (SCI, Q1)
- 5. Xuan-Duong Nguyen, Anh-Khoa Nguyen Vu, **Thanh-Danh Nguyen**, Nguyen Phan, Bao-Duy Duyen Dinh, Nhat-Duy Nguyen, Tam V. Nguyen, Vinh-Tiep Nguyen, and Duy-Dinh Le, "Adaptive multi-vehicle motion counting", *Signal, Image and Video Processing (SIVIP)*, Feb 2022. IF = 2.157 (SCIE, Q2)

Please visit my portfolio for the full list (danhntd.github.io/research.html)

AWARDS AND HONORS

- Best Student Paper Award at 2023 International Conference on Multimedia Analysis and Pattern Recognition (MAPR)
- Master, PhD Scholarship Programme of Vingroup Innovation Foundation VinIF, code VINIF.2022.ThS.104, in 2022
- Two scholarships for Excellence of **Pony Chung Foundation** in 2019 and 2020
- Consolation Prize in AI City Challenge Ho Chi Minh City 2020: Vehicle Motion Counting [5]
- Scholarship for Excellence of BIDV Corp. in 2018
- Scholarships for Excellence in GPA (top 8% of students): Under-graduate (2019-2021) and Post-graduate (2022-2023)

SKILLS

- Computer Vision, AI, Machine Learning, Deep Learning
- Python, PyTorch, Tensorflow, and Linux server techniques
- Research and teaching skills
- Foreign language: English (IELTS 6.5)

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- UIT Leaders, Youth Union Officials (2017–2021)
- Active member of Open English Club (2017–2020)
- Joined Volunteer Works: "UP" Volunteer Campaign (2017), UIT Grow 1000 trees (2018)

REFERENCES

• Dr. Tiep Nguyen (Thesis advisor)

Head of Multimedia Lab., University of Information Technology, VNU-HCM, HCMC, Vietnam

Contact: tiepnv (at) uit.edu.vn

• Assoc. Prof. Tam V. Nguyen (Research advisor)

Founder of Vision and Mixed Reality Lab., University of Dayton, Dayton, OH 45469, United States

Contact: tamnguyen (at) udayton.edu; Website: vantam.github.io